<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Maya&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Maya&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Maya Ayoubi. I look at numbers and tell stories.
Aside from being able to tell you what&amp;rsquo;s hiding in the number forest, I enjoy cooking, baking, and all things involving the kitchen.
This site is where I intertwine my experiences of software, food, odds, and ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yosemite Fall 2020</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/yosemite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/yosemite/</guid>
      <description>Falling in love with Yosemite in the fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hummus Recipe</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/hummus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/hummus/</guid>
      <description>About Hummus is a Middle Eastern dip made from chickpeas, tahini, lemon, and spices. It can be found in many grocery stores in North America and Europe, but it&amp;rsquo;s so easy and fast to make that I recommend making your own! Here, I throw a curve ball and add some yogurt to add richness and parsley for some color.
Serving Size 5-6
Ingredients  15 oz can of garbanzo beans 3 tablespoons freshly squeezed lemon juice 2 medium size garlic cloves, minced 1 tablespoon tahini 1 tablespoon whole milk plain yogurt 1 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon olive oil Powdered sumac or smoked paprika (optional) Handful of parsley (optional)  Instructions 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knafeh Recipe</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/knafeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/knafeh/</guid>
      <description>About Knafeh, an amazing Middle Eastern dessert made with thin shredded filo noodles (or semolina dough), sweet cheese, clotted cream, or nut filling, and soaked in a sugar based syrup.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved knafeh growing up, but as a vegan teenager I needed to find a way to make a dairy free kind. But how? with coconut milk, of course! Years later with my veganism behind me, I still find myself preferring my vegan recipe over the traditional cheese knafeh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shakshouka Recipe</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/shakshouka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/shakshouka/</guid>
      <description>About Shakshouka, a Tunisian dish that is &amp;ldquo;all mixed up&amp;rdquo;. What? That&amp;rsquo;s what it translates to in Arabic! This tomato based stew is filled with bold flavors and spices great anytime of the day.
Serving Size 2-3
Ingredients  3 tablespoons avocado oil 1 onion, chopped 1 red bell pepper, seeded and chopped 2 garlic cloves, minced 2 teaspoons tomato paste 1 teaspoon ground cumin 1 teaspoon turmeric 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon smoked paprika 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon grinded rainbow peppercorns 1&amp;frasl;8 teaspoon of red pepper flakes (optional) 1&amp;frasl;8 teaspoon cayenne pepper 12 oz fire roasted red peppers, chopped coarse 1 can (14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baklawa Recipe</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/baklawa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 13:11:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/baklawa/</guid>
      <description>About Baklawa is a rich filo and nut pastry that is smothered in syrup or honey. It&amp;rsquo;s so good that every country wants to claim it as their own, but suffice to say that it is made in MENA, Turkey, Southeast Europe, and Central Asia.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my Lebanese style baklawa where a rose and orange blossom water based syrup is used instead of honey! I put a little spin on things by replacing the traditonal walnut or pistachio filling with the nut from the American south, pecans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halawet El Jibn Recipe</title>
      <link>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/halaweteljibn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 13:11:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ayoubimaya.github.io/post/halaweteljibn/</guid>
      <description>About Halawet El Jibn, my favorite pastry as a kid until now! A classic Levantine dessert that is more fluffy and rich than it is sweet. People don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily think of cheese when they think dessert, but one taste of this delectable delicacy will change your mind! Unlike other Levantine desserts (think Knafeh), Halawet el Jibn is great at any temperature!
Ingredients For Syrup  2 cups granulated sugar 1 cup water 1&amp;frasl;2 teaspoon freshly squeezed lemon juice 3&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon orange blossom water 3&amp;frasl;4 teaspoon rose water  For Halawet El Jibn (Sweet cheese rolls)  1 1&amp;frasl;2 cup of water 3&amp;frasl;4 cup sugar 1 cup fine semolina 28 g of sweet cheese (or mozzarella cheese), shredded or sliced thin 1 tablespoon rose water 1 tablespoon orange blossom water   For Filling  8 oz of mascarpone cheese 1 tablespoon of almond milk 1&amp;frasl;4 cup shredded sweet cheese (or mozzarella)  Instructions Making Syrup 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>